# Breno Aquino Software Developer

**GitHub** 

**BrenoAquino** 

LinkedIn

**BrenoAquino** 

**Email** 

brenoaquino7phr@gmail.com

#### **About**

I have worked as an iOS Developer for more than 6 years and have mentored interns and juniors during my professional journey. I'm always looking for performance, innovation and automation, and how I can apply these concepts in the project, process or life. I have experience with projects in the areas of streaming, finance and education. I also have experience in creating SDKs, both for internal use and for sale to third parties.

## **Professional Experience**

Rakuten, United States/Canada · Remote

iOS Developer

October 2022 - current

- Responsible for creating an analytics SDK for internal use by the company with the aim of obtaining higher
  quality data to facilitate the mapping of product improvements. As the SDK could be called by any
  component at any time, it was necessary to create thread safe components, and to ensure this I created unit
  tests creating multiple threads and trying to access the resource at the same time. Test coverage for the SDK
  was around 92%;
- The analytics SDK was also created to support different countries and each with its own domain. There is a buffer to avoid excessive requests and each buffer is linked to the country of the user who generated the events;
- Worked on migrating authentication to using a WebView in which it talked to the app through JavaScript messages;
- Improved the privacy flow with the aim of facilitating expansion to other states/countries that follow different privacy laws;
- Responsible for creating components to serve as bridges between RxSwift that we are removing from the
  project and Combine. The objective was that new features and refactorings do not use third-party
  frameworks, but to talk to existing components, the mentioned classes would be used.

ĺ	:00	1	Cwift	ľ	CwiftIII	lſ	Combine	1	Unit Tooting	ľ	VCToot	ì	Xcode Cloud	)	Faatlana	$\Gamma$	CDI	_
	105	Ш	Swift		SWITTUI	Ш	Combine	Ш	Unit Testing	Ш	XClest	ш	- Xcode Cloud	ш	Fastiane		SDE	(

Itaú, Brazil · Remote

iOS Developer

March 2022 - October 2022

- Responsible for leading and guiding a Junior developer with an emphasis on iOS development. I was
  responsible for meeting with him every week to answer questions and generally providing a collection of
  articles on the study topic selected at the time. We also communicate during the week to help with
  development and help with code reviews;
- As the company has a significant number of developers and dozens of squads, we used several repositories for each module and a main one with the app focused on integrating and coordinating the app's navigation. All module distributions were using cocoapods;

- To support multiple apps in the App Store and avoid duplicate code, it was configured different build schemas and build configurations to define how some components/modules should behave and look;
- Responsible for creating and maintaining multiple modules related to the app's notification/deeplink flow, the app had about 28.000.000 active user per month;
- Worked on redesigning the app, where I could apply improvements to the app's architecture and making it more testable and maintainable.

```
[iOS] Swift UIKit View Code Unit Testing XCTest Modules Swift Package Manager Cocoapods Jenkins Fastlane
```

#### Meta, United States/Canada · Remote

iOS Developer

December 2020 - February 2022 (part time)

- Worked as a leader creating and defining the base structure project for the client Maple Leaf Sports & Entertainment (MLSE). Defining the priority of features, architectures, APIs and web socket messages for real-time behavior;
- Used the RTSP protocol to load Live content, but we also provide compatibility for VOD content. The idea was publish the best moments of the game as VOD;
- The aim of the project was to be integrable with any team app. For this, an interface was defined that the host app would implement to configure the SDK theme, being able to modify colors and logo in some locations;
- To respond to events happening in the game in real time, it was necessary to create a web socket connection with the server. With this, the app could respond in real time with: trivia, advertising/celebration banners and mini games using web view to load them.
- A chat was also developed to send/receive messages among all users, as well as the possibility of creating groups which would exist only for that game;
- As it was an SDK used internally but could be sold for integration into third-party teams, it was necessary to
  configure CI/CD to publish an already compiled version of the SDK and its documentation in a public
  repository, along with a sample app to guide integration with the SDK;
- Implemented the SDK following MVVM and Clean Architecture to meet the mentioned requirements and provide good maintainability and scalability.

```
    iOS
    Swift
    UIKit
    View Code
    Unit Testing
    Streaming
    Quick
    Nimble
    XCTest
    WebSocket
    SDK
    Cocoapods
    CI/CD

    Github Actions
```

#### Claro, São Paulo - SP, Brazil

iOS Developer

March 2019 - March 2022

- Worked on 2 streaming projects, one created from scratch and another that was already in production with around 300.000 active users per month. Both of them provided live and VOD contents;
- Implemented Fairplay DRM for live and VOD content. It was necessary to use two different logics since each
  video type worked in a different way. I created an abstraction layer so that the player accepted different DRM
  implementations;
- Handled different types of VOD such as: multi audio where the audio and subtitle track was disconnected
  from the video and the user could change any audio/subtitle track without reloading the media; single audio
  where the audio and subtitles were inserted directly into the media, to change the audio or subtitles it was
  necessary to load a new media with a predefined configuration, it was not possible to choose just the audio or
  just the subtitles, the user was forced to change both tracks together; DVB where the subtitle was received in
  base64 and it was necessary to display it as an image over the content;
- Implemented an architecture with multiple repositories to facilitate maintainability and scalability. There was a
  repository containing all the business rules and this was imported using swift package manage both into
  the iOS app repository and would be imported into the Apple TV app when it was developed;

- All new features were covered by unit tests and aiming for 80% coverage;
- Implemented a feature to list all channels and their programs, to improve the performance and the time to render the screen to the user, I implemented a custom cache algorithm to avoid unnecessary recalculations and binary search to improve the time to find the current program based on the time.

```
      [iOS] Swift] UIKit
      View Code
      Unit Testing
      Streaming
      Quick
      Nimble
      XCTest
      Swift Package Manager
      CI/CD

      Fastlane
      Bitrise
```

## Education

## University of Fortaleza - UNIFOR

Graduation, Computing Engineering

2015 - 2019

- Final Project: Research using recurrent neural networks to predict cryptocurrency trends.
- Object Orientation class assistant in 2016.
- Microprocessor class assistant in 2017.
- Researcher in the area of sensor network security, trying to implement an algorithm to detect attacks.